<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dmodule>
  <ident>
    <dmAddress>
      <dmIdent>
        <dmCode modelIdentCode="TIQ" systemCode="99" subSystemCode="01" issueNumber="001" inWork="00" infoCode="MNT" itemLocationCode="0001" />
        <language countryIsoCode="US" languageIsoCode="en" />
      </dmIdent>
      <dmTitle>
        <techName>Token Refresh and SignalR Reconnection Failure</techName>
        <infoName>System Bug Report</infoName>
      </dmTitle>
    </dmAddress>
  </ident>

  <content>
    <description>
      <para>This data module documents a recurring midnight issue in the TIQ application where silent OAuth2 token refresh fails, leading to infinite SignalR reconnection loops and degraded platform performance.</para>
    </description>

    <fault>
      <symptom>TIQ fails to automatically refresh consult/scheduled data post-midnight. UI becomes unresponsive until a manual reload.</symptom>
      <cause>Expired authentication tokens are reused with stale PKCE parameters, triggering 400 errors from Okta. Concurrent SignalR re-initiation fails due to timing mismatches and missing transport initialization.</cause>
      <remedy>
        <step>Ensure fresh PKCE parameters are generated before each silent OAuth2 refresh attempt.</step>
        <step>Fix race conditions between SignalR HubConnection stop() and start() methods using internal locking or debounce logic.</step>
        <step>Audit beforeunload event listeners for incomplete cleanup routines; implement fallback logic using pagehide if applicable.</step>
        <step>Log all renewal attempts, state transitions, and token expiration timestamps for auditability and replay debugging.</step>
      </remedy>
    </fault>

    <figure>
      <title>Timeline of Issue Reproduction</title>
      <para>Screenshot logs and stack traces confirm an expired token around 00:43:03, multiple failed OAuth requests, and a cascade of HubConnection.start() / stop() overlap errors. Recovery only occurs after manual page refresh.</para>
    </figure>

    <remarks>
      <para>Documentation based on analysis by Haily Stevens, 2025-04-04, including annotated HAR logs, console transcripts, and observed UI states. Refer to linked screenshots for correlation between logs and root cause.</para>
    </remarks>
  </content>
</dmodule>
